[Opening Theme Music - Full translation available in Ep. 1]
[Opening Theme Music - Full translation available in Ep. 1]
Mojo Mojo Mojo Spy
Mojo Mojo Mojo Spy
Mojo Spy
Mojo Spy
Let's go!
Let's go!
This world's a colorful, hazy blue
这个世界五彩泛蓝
Truth and lies confuse our view
真真假假迷惑我们的眼
Use your heart to see it through
用你的心认真去看
Find the truth right under you
发现真相就在处院
Hey you good or bad, truth or lies
Hey you good or bad 真真假假
Step out from the mental disguise
踏步出这心灵的灰烟
Take all your courage, don't be shy
带上你的所有勇敢
Maybe you can save the sky
也许就能拯救这世界
Mojo Mojo Mojo Spy
Mojo Mojo Mojo Spy
Mojo Spy
Mojo Spy
Locky Qi and Hawxing investigate together and find
齐乐天与霍星一起调查发现
On the night of the crime, guard Lei Jie acted suspiciously
案发当晚，保安雷杰形迹可疑
They decide to check out Lei Jie's place for a clue
他们决定去雷杰家一探究竟
The Illumin-Eye
光明之眼
Huh?
嗯？
I don't remember seeing this juice box last time I came
我记得上次来的时候 没有见到这个果汁箱啊
Ah, juice!
啊 果汁！
What the heck? [DVD: Dead Chicken]
什么嘛 【DVD: 丧鸡】
This isn't juice!
这不是果汁啊
I've been looking for this movie forever.
我找这个电影好久了
Never thought I'd find it here—ha!
没想到在这里找到 哈哈
It's starting, it's starting, it's starting!
开始了 开始了 开始了
Hello, dear viewers~
各位观众朋友~
What's this nonsense?
搞什么嘛
It's Smile Match!
居然是微笑对对碰
And it's from the day before yesterday!
而且还是前天
Are you sure this is from the day before yesterday?
你确定这是前天的节目
Of course!
那当然
I watch it on time every day.
我每天准时收看
What time does this show air daily?
这个节目每天什么时候播出
Are you from Mars?
你是火星人吗
A show this popular,
这么有人气的节目
and you don't know its airtime?
你居然不知道播出时间
It's 11:30 PM every day, of course!
当然是每天的23点30了
Let's go talk to the apartment manager.
我们去跟公寓负责人聊聊
Excuse me, do you know Lei Jie who lives here?
请问您认不认识住在这里的雷杰
Lei Jie?
雷杰
Of course I do.
当然认识
That guy has no hygiene—
这个人不讲卫生
he tosses trash anywhere, and won't listen to warnings.
垃圾随便扔警告他他也不听
Do you remember the night before last,
那您记不记得前天晚上
after the 11 PM curfew, Lei Jie came back?
公寓二十三点门禁后雷杰才回来
And even got scolded by you.
还被您训了一顿
Every day when he comes back, I tell him—
他每天回来我都跟他说
Take out the trash!
把垃圾处理掉！
But he just won’t listen.
可他就是不听
Also, our building is open 24 hours.
还有 我们公寓是二十四小时开放的
Where’s the curfew?
哪里来的门禁
The night before last, Lei Jie brought this foreigner back around eight.
前天晚上雷杰八点左右带着这个外国人回来
Then he ran out again and didn’t come back till dawn.
然后自己又跑出去直到凌晨才回来
No idea what he was up to.
不知道搞什么
How does that match Mr. K’s timeline at all?
怎么跟Mr.K说的时间完全不一样啊？
I already know who the culprit is.
我已经知道罪犯是谁了
Let’s talk back at the station.
回警局再说
Thanks for the tip.
感谢你提供线索
Mister in charge.
负责人先生
Bye-bye.
拜拜
Hello, who’s this?
哈喽 哪位
Hey, I’ve already been spotted by that little detective.
喂 我已经被小侦探盯上了
Pay me the rest of the money now.
赶紧把剩余的钱付给我
I need to lay low.
我要去避避风头
Lei Jie, you’re too naive.
雷杰 你太天真了
You were just a pawn.
你只不过是为了一颗棋子
Now you’re of no use anymore.
现在你已经没有任何利用价值了
You jerk.
你这个混蛋
How dare you treat me like this?
居然敢这样对我
You’re the one who ordered me.
是你指使我的
Aren't you afraid I'll rat you out?
你就不怕我把你供出来吗
Haha~ Right now, all the evidence points to
哈哈~现在所有的证据都表明
you being the criminal.
你是罪犯
And you're the only one who actually stole the gem.
而且动手偷宝石的也只有你
Who'd believe your story?
谁会相信你的话
Hahahahaha!
哈哈哈哈哈
Mr. Lei Jie, in a fine mood,
雷杰先生 好兴致啊
enjoying the sunset all alone, are we?
独自一人在欣赏夕阳的美景吗
Go!
上
You looking for me?
你们找我有事吗
The one who used the invisibility watch
借用隐身手表
to steal the gem, Angel's Tears,
偷走宝石天使之泪的那个人
is you.
就是你
Haha, absurd, absurd!
哈哈哈 荒谬荒谬
When the crime happened, I was with Mr. K.
发案时我和Mr.K在一起
I have a witness!
我有人证啊
You got Mr. K drunk first,
你先把Mr.K灌醉
then helped him back to your apartment.
然后把他扶回你的公寓
The strange accent of the apartment manager's scolding
公寓负责人训斥的奇怪口音
was explained by you as a curfew warning,
被你解释成门禁的警告
to give the drunken Mr. K
以便给醉酒的Mr.K
the impression it was already late.
留下当时已经很晚的印象
But in reality,
实际呢
the actual time
当时的时间
was still far from 23:00.
离23点还相差很远
Don't forget—
你们别忘了
At 11:30 PM,
23点30分的时候
I was with Mr. K,
我正和Mr.K一起
watching TV at home.
在家里看电视
Hmph. You waited until Mr. K
哼 你等Mr.K
fell asleep in your bed,
在你床上睡着后
used the VCR's auto-record function
用录像机自动录制功能
to tape the TV show,
把电视节目录到录像带上
then stole Mr. K's keys
然后偷走Mr.K的钥匙
and robbed the museum between 11:30 and midnight.
在23点30分到博物馆行窃
When you got back early morning,
待你凌晨回来后
you played the pre-recorded
你先用电视播放
Smile Match on the TV,
已经录制好的微笑对对碰
then woke up a groggy Mr. K,
再叫醒迷迷糊糊的Mr.K
handed him a hangover pill,
说给他解酒药
and faked being home the whole time.
制造出你一直带在公寓的假象
But you overlooked the apartment manager—
可是你忽视了公寓的负责人
because of your hygiene issues,
他因为你的个人卫生问题
he remembered your comings and goings clearly.
对你的出行时间记忆深刻
And your fake alibi
而且你编造出的虚假门禁
along with the forgotten tape
和忘记销毁的录像带
became your Achilles' heel!
都成为你的 死穴！
I only stole to support my family.
我只是为了养家糊口才行窃的
Was I really wrong?
难道我真的错了吗
Was I... really wrong?
难道 我真的错了吗
Aaaahhh!
啊啊啊啊
I was blind to trust
只怪我瞎了眼睛
that venomous snake I worked for—!!
为那个蛇蝎心肠的人卖命——！！
After him!
追！
Ah! He's fast.
啊！他逃得好快
Didn't expect him to be so agile.
想不到他身手如此敏捷
Captain, don't rush.
队长 不要急
Even if it costs me everything,
我司马刚就算肝脑涂地
I, Sima Gang, will bring that crook to justice.
也要把坏人绳之以法
For the people's sake.
为了人民的利益
Right on time.
正好赶上
You—
你——
Trying to run after being exposed?
被揭穿就想逃跑
Move aside!
快闪开
Hehe, no way.
嘻嘻 偏不要
You're asking for it.
你找死
[XX-rated scene—viewers under 18 not allowed]
[XX级镜头 十八岁以下禁止观看]
Still trying to run?
还敢逃吗
Uncle!
老舅
Great, Detective Chen.
太好了 陈侦探
Lei Jie.
雷杰
As a security officer, you stole from your own post.
你身为警卫人员却坚守自盗
I'm arresting you now.
我现在逮捕你
Anything to say for yourself?
你还有什么好说的
Caught by you.
栽在你们手上
Just my luck.
算我倒霉
But I was set up by someone.
但我是被人指使的
He used me and then threw me under the bus.
他达成目的后就出卖了我
I'm gonna rat him out.
我一定要把他供出来
The real mastermind is...
真正的幕后黑手就是
Mr. K.
Mr.K
About a week ago,
就在一个礼拜之前
Mr. K was transporting gems to the museum for an exhibition.
Mr.K运送宝石来博物馆准备展出
Secretly, he bribed me heavily to steal the gems,
暗地里他用重金收买我盗窃宝石
promising I'd get away clean.
被承诺事后一定让我全身而退
Back then, I was blinded by greed and agreed without a second thought.
当时我利欲熏心地就爽快地答应了
On the night of the heist,
行窃当晚
he said we'd hit a bar to celebrate early.
他说要和我提前去酒吧庆祝
Then he insisted on checking out my apartment.
之后他又说要参观一下我的公寓
At the apartment entrance,
在公寓门口
I got chewed out by the building manager
我又因为卫生问题
over some hygiene issues.
被公寓负责人训了一顿
Mr. K seemed pretty intrigued by that.
Mr. K听了仿佛很感兴趣
Back in the apartment,
回到了公寓
he handed me the invisibility watch and the vault key,
他将隐身手表和保险库钥匙交给我
telling me to pull the heist at exactly 11:30 PM.
要我在23点30分准时行窃
When I got back,
等我回来的时候
I found him recording the Smile Match show.
发现他正在录制微笑对对碰节目
He said he was really into the show
他说他对这个节目很感兴趣
and told me to keep the tape safe.
要我把录像带妥善地保管
Give it to him after he leaves.
等到他离开的时候再给他
But I never imagined...
可是我万万没有想到啊
All of this was carefully planned by him—
这一切都是他精心设计的
A trap!
陷阱！
See? See?
你看你看
I suspected Mr. K all along.
我早就怀疑过Mr.K
You guys just didn't believe me.
你们却不相信我
Did Mr. K ever tell you
Mr.K是否跟你说过
what his purpose was for stealing the gem?
他盗窃宝石的目的是什么
I overheard him contacting someone.
我无意间听到过他和别人联系
Sounded like a deal.
好像是一次交易
The meeting place was...
交易的地点就在
There's a light!
有道光
It's Mr. K.
是Mr.K
Almost ruined by this idiot.
差点被这个笨蛋坏了好事
So you really are the mastermind.
原来你真的是幕后黑手
Better surrender quietly now.
赶快乖乖束手就擒吧
Catching me won't be that easy.
想抓住我恐怕没有那么容易
Take our 'Love and Ideals'
带上我们的‘爱与梦想’
and soar freely in the sky!
在天空自由翱翔吧
The big villain is getting away!
大坏蛋要跑了
Open fire!
开火
Obstructing the Illumin-Eye's sacred plan—
阻碍光明之眼的神圣计划
you will pay the price!
你们一定会付出代价的
You're a big, bad villain! A big, bad villain!
你是大坏蛋大坏蛋
Big bad guy, big bad guy
大坏蛋大坏蛋
Is it The Illumin-Eye?
是光明之眼吗
Subtitle Volunteer: Yang Xixi
字幕志愿者 杨茜茜
YoYo Television Series Exclusive
优优独播剧场——YoYo Television Series Exclusive